The following content is provided
提供以下内容
under a Creative Commons license.
根据知识共享许可。
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue
您的支持将帮助MIT OpenCourseWare继续
to offer high quality educational resources for free.
免费提供高质量的教育资源。
To make a donation, or view additional materials
捐款或查看其他材料
from hundreds of MIT courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare
从数百门麻省理工学院的课程中，访问MIT OpenCourseWare
at ocw.mit.edu.
在ocw.mit.edu。
PROFESSOR: The things we can talk about today, we
教授：我们今天可以谈论的事情，我们
can talk about this code.
可以谈谈这段代码。
We can talk a little bit more about the hash functions.
我们可以多说一些哈希函数。
And we can talk a little bit more about amortization.
我们可以谈谈更多有关摊销的内容。
What to do guys want to hear?
家伙想听些什么？
AUDIENCE: Amoritizaiton.
听众：Amoritizaiton。
PROFESSOR: OK, so one vote for amortization.
教授：好的，所以一票赞成摊销。
So who wants to look at the PSET code?
那么，谁想看一下PSET代码？
Who wants to talk about hashes?
谁想谈论哈希？
Who wants to talk about amortization?
谁想谈谈摊销？
Two, three, four, five, OK.
二，三，四，五，好的。
So then let's try this.
因此，让我们尝试一下。
Let's look at the PSET code then talk about amortization a bit
让我们看一下PSET代码，然后再讨论摊销
at the end.
在末尾。
I do have to talk a little bit about hashes
我确实要谈一些哈希
though, because I owe someone a question from last time.
但是，因为我上次欠某人一个问题。
And the question was, we have rolling hashes,
问题是，我们有滚动哈希，
so the hashes look like this.
所以哈希看起来像这样
K where K is a big number, modulo p.
K，其中K是大数，模为p。
And we argue that it's really nice if p is a prime.
而且我们认为，如果p是质数，那真的很好。
And then the question was, what if instead p is 2 to the w,
然后问题是，如果p相对于w为2，该怎么办？
and is not prime, as long as the base that we're using
并且不是素数，只要我们使用的基础
is co-prime with p?
是p的素数？
Does this work?
这样行吗？
And the answer is-- I didn't want
答案是-我不想
to say yes without making sure that I don't say something
在不确保我不说话的情况下说是
stupid-- but the answer is yes, this
愚蠢的-但答案是肯定的，这
works just fine, because the way a compute multiplicative
效果很好，因为计算乘法的方式
inverse is is you use so something
反之是你用了什么
called the extended Euclid's method.
称为扩展的欧几里得方法。
And if we have b and p, then if we compute their GCD,
如果我们有b和p，那么如果我们计算它们的GCD，
the that's the greatest common divisor-- so GCD is greatest--
那是最大的公约数-所以GCD也是最大的-
If you use extended Euclid you get something like xb plus yp
如果您使用扩展的Euclid，则会得到类似xb和yp的信息
equals GCD of b and p.
等于b和p的GCD。
So if this is 1, then you have xb plus yp equals 1.
因此，如果这是1，则xb加yp等于1。
And if you're working modulo p, whatever that is,
如果您正在对p取模，不管是什么，
then you have that xb is 1 mod p.
则xb为1 mod p。
So there's your multiplicative inverse.
因此，存在您的乘法逆。
Well so now that's nice math, right?
好了，现在算是好数学了，对吧？
But that doesn't tell me why are we not using this.
但这并不能告诉我为什么我们不使用它。
So with the multiplicative inverse would work,
因此，通过乘法逆可以工作，
but there's something else that's
但是还有其他的东西
wrong with using 2 to the w.
对w使用2是错误的。
Will this give me a good hash function?
这会给我一个好的哈希函数吗？
OK, the fact that it's p might be confusing.
好吧，事实是p可能令人困惑。
So let's say h equals K mod 2 to the w.
因此，假设h等于w的K mod 2。
And remember that the K is some digits in base b, right?
还记得K是底数b的数字吗？
It's a big number made out of digits in base b.
这是一个很大的数字，由基数b中的数​​字组成。
So K is d1, d2, d3, all the way up until d length in base b.
因此K一直是d1，d2，d3，一直到基b中的d长度为止。
And I'll make things easier and say that b is 2 to the 8,
我会让事情变得容易些，并说b是8的2。
because we're working with ASCII characters, or colors,
因为我们正在使用ASCII字符或颜色，
or something that fits nicely in a bit.
或非常适合的东西。
So what could go wrong with using this?
那么使用此功能可能出什么问题呢？
AUDIENCE: Well if your series of-- if your K is bigger than
听众：如果您的系列-如果您的K大于
2-- if it's K is bigger than 2 to the w--
2--如果K大于w的2-
PROFESSOR: It will be, for sure.
教授：当然可以。
AUDIENCE: Yes, that's the problem, because then you'll
听众：是的，这就是问题所在，因为那样您会
loop.
环。
You'll get the same hashes for--
您会为...获得相同的哈希值
PROFESSOR: Yeah, yeah.
教授：是的，是的。
So you will get-- So hashing takes a lot of possible inputs
这样您将获得-因此散列需要大量可能的输入
and maps them to a relatively small set of outputs.
并将它们映射到相对较小的一组输出。
Inputs hash output.
输入哈希输出。
And we argued last time that we're
上次我们争论说
going to have collisions no matter what,
不管发生什么碰撞
because we have a ton of inputs and not that many outputs.
因为我们有大量的投入，却没有那么多的产出。
For example, if we're hashing strings
例如，如果我们要对字符串进行哈希处理
that are a million characters then this
那是一百万个字符
is going to be 2 to the 8 to the 1 million possible strings.
将是2到8到100万个可能的字符串。
And then the number of possible values
然后是可能值的数量
is, if we're using the word size, 2 to the 32.
是，如果我们使用字长，则2到32。
There is no way we can design a function that
我们无法设计一个可以
will take this many inputs, map them to this many outputs,
将接受这么多输入，将它们映射到这么多输出，
and not do collisions.
而不做碰撞。
But instead, what do we want?
但是，相反，我们想要什么？
What makes a good hash function?
什么使一个好的哈希函数？
Say my hash function is 0 for all the K's.
假设我的哈希函数对于所有K均为0。
Is that a good hash function?
那是一个很好的哈希函数吗？
AUDIENCE: It's an excellent hash function.
听众：这是一个出色的哈希函数。
PROFESSOR: What's wrong with it?
教授：怎么了？
AUDIENCE: You would put everything in one
观众：您可以将所有内容合而为一
so that it's searching, or it would take a long time?
以便进行搜索，或者需要很长时间？
PROFESSOR: Yeah, searching takes a long time.
教授：是的，搜索需要很长时间。
And we've don't do sorting with this yet.
而且我们还没有对此进行排序。
Searching takes a long time, string sub-matching
搜索需要很长时间，字符串子匹配
will take a long time, it's horrible.
需要很长时间，这太可怕了。
AUDIENCE: So what would that distribute--
听众：那会散布什么呢？
like [INAUDIBLE] over all--
像[音频不清晰]
PROFESSOR: All right, so we want something
教授：好的，所以我们想要一些东西
that looks sort of random.
看起来有点随机。
The ideals hash function takes an input then
理想哈希函数接受输入，然后
gives it a random output, and then stays consistent.
给它一个随机输出，然后保持一致。
So when it sees an input, returns the same output.
因此，当看到输入时，将返回相同的输出。
So I think distribute is the keyword here.
所以我认为分发是这里的关键词。
What's wrong with this hash function?
此哈希函数有什么问题？
If it takes random data, it's going
如果需要随机数据，它将
to distribute it randomly.
随机分发。
That's true, so that's all good.
是的，所以一切都很好。
But what data that we might see in real life
但是我们在现实生活中可能会看到哪些数据
will make it behave badly?
会使其表现不佳吗？
AUDIENCE: The K is a series of characters, right?
听众：K是一系列字符，对吗？
PROFESSOR: Maybe.
教授：也许吧。
AUDIENCE: It just could be anything.
听众：什么都可以。
But we know for sure that L will be larger than w.
但是我们肯定知道L会大于w。
PROFESSOR: Say L is a million.
教授：说L是一百万。
AUDIENCE: OK, well that sucks.
听众：好吧，那太糟了。
PROFESSOR: Oh, no.
教授：哦，不。
That in itself, that doesn't suck.
就其本身而言，那并不烂。
That's what let's us do sub-string matching really
这就是让我们真正进行子字符串匹配的原因
fast, even if we have large strings.
即使我们有很大的弦，速度也很快。
AUDIENCE: --say for 2 to the w, though,
听众：-比方说2对w
because then it will be much larger, like the number of--
因为那样的话，它将变得更大，就像-
PROFESSOR: Yeah, but that's OK.
教授：是的，但是可以。
So I'm OK with doing this as long as all the values here
所以我可以这样做，只要这里的所有值
are distributed sort of uniformly here.
在这里均匀地分布。
So that's fine.
这样很好
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
PROFESSOR: But there's-- I'm arguing that there are some
教授：但是-我是在争论
values which will make this hash function behave badly.
值会使该哈希函数的行为不佳。
And that those values are so simple that we might see them
这些值是如此简单，以至于我们可能会看到它们
in real life.
在真实生活中。
OK, what if all these numbers are-- what
好吧，如果所有这些数字都是-怎么办
if all the digits are even?
如果所有数字都是偶数？
So d is 0 mod 2.
所以d是0 mod 2。
What happens to K?
K会发生什么？
AUDIENCE: Well, you're saying that instead of 2 to the w,
听众：嗯，你是说而不是w的2，
we're just using 2.
我们只是在使用2。
PROFESSOR: So no, the modulo is 2 to the w.
教授：所以不，模数是w的2。
Say it's 2 to the 32.
说32的2。
So d are the digits that make up my K. So what
d是构成我的K的数字。那么
if the base is 2 to the 8?
如果基数是2到8？
So I have digits from 0 to 255, 256 of them.
所以我有0到255之间的数字，其中有256位。
And all the digits are 0 modulo 2.
并且所有数字均为0模2。
For my sub-string matching example,
对于我的子字符串匹配示例，
what if all the characters in the sub-string are even?
如果子字符串中的所有字符都是偶数怎么办？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
PROFESSOR: Not the same thing.
教授：不一样。
But there's a problem.
但是有一个问题。
They will hash to-- so if all the digits are
他们将散列到-因此，如果所有数字都是
0 modulo 2 then what about the K?
0模2那么K呢？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] 0 modulo 2--
听众：[听不清] 0模2
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
So it's just like when you have numbers in base 10.
因此，就像以10为底的数字一样。
10 happens to be divisible by 2.
10恰好可被2整除。
So if your last digit is even, then the entire number is even.
因此，如果您的最后一位数字是偶数，则整个数字是偶数。
That makes sense, right?
那是有道理的，对吧？
That's math.
那是数学。
Please nod, tell me that I'm making sense.
请点头，告诉我，我有道理。
OK, so here, the base is 256.
好的，所以这里的底数是256。
And it's also divisible by 2.
而且也可以被2整除。
So if your last digit is divisible by 2,
因此，如果您的最后一位数字可被2整除，
then the whole number is divisible by 2.
则整数可被2整除。
So then if I take this K modulo 2 to the 32
所以如果我把这个K模2取到32
then the hash is also going to be divisible by 2.
那么散列也将被2整除。
AUDIENCE: Why does it matter if the hash is divisible by 2?
听众：如果哈希可以被2整除，那为什么很重要？
PROFESSOR: So it matters because this
教授：这很重要，因为这
is supposed to be my universe, right?
应该是我的宇宙吧？
These are supposed to be all the outputs.
这些应该是所有输出。
And I'm saying that if my inputs look like this,
我是说，如果我的输入看起来像这样，
then the hash function will not distribute them uniformly.
那么散列函数将不会将它们均匀分布。
Instead, if this is my possible set of outputs,
相反，如果这是我可能的一组输出，
the hash function will always put outputs in this half.
哈希函数将始终将输出放在这一半。
So the outputs will always be here.
因此，输出将始终在此处。
And these are the numbers that are divisible by 2.
这些是可以被2整除的数字。
So these are even, and these are odd.
所以这些都是偶数，这些都是奇数。
And this area gets no love.
而且这个地区没有爱。
Absolutely no number will hash here.
绝对没有数字会在这里散列。
So--
所以 -
AUDIENCE: Wait, what about something with all odds?
听众：等等，万事大吉怎么办？
AUDIENCE: Something with all odd digits?
听众：东西全都是奇数？
AUDIENCE: Because you're asking--
听众：因为你在问-
AUDIENCE: You have all A's rather than
听众：您拥有所有A，而不是
all B's in your sub-string or in your string.
您的子字符串或字符串中的所有B。
AUDIENCE: Or because your last digit was odd.
听众：或者因为您的最后一位数字是奇数。
PROFESSOR: If all of our digits are odd
教授：如果我们所有的数字都是奇数
then the last digit is odd.
那么最后一位是奇数。
And then you'd also get something odd, right?
然后你也会得到一些奇怪的东西，对吧？
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
AUDIENCE: So there's a pattern.
听众：所以有一种模式。
But there's an even distribution.
但分布均匀。
PROFESSOR: Well if your hash function is always odd,
教授：如果您的哈希函数始终是奇数，
then it's not an even distribution.
那就不是均匀分布。
It's--
它的 -
AUDIENCE: Wait, our hash function?
听众：等等，我们的哈希函数？
I thought we were talking about--
我以为我们在谈论-
AUDIENCE: Isn't it even if your K is even?
听众：即使您的K等于偶数吗？
And if it's odd [INAUDIBLE]?
如果奇怪[听不清]？
PROFESSOR: Yeah, so that's bad.
教授：是的，这很糟糕。
Because if all your K's happens to be even--
因为如果您所有的K碰巧是偶数-
say if you're doing the nucleotides,
说如果你正在做核苷酸，
and the nucleotides are A, C, G, T.
核苷酸是A，C，G，T。
If they happen to be encoded as, say, 0, 2, 4, 6,
如果碰巧将它们编码为0、2、4、6
then these are all even.
然后这些都是偶数。
So the hash function will always be even
因此哈希函数将始终是偶数
and I'm wasting the last bit.
我在浪费最后一点。
So if I'm building a hash table, half the entries
因此，如果我要构建哈希表，则一半的条目
will be wasted.
将被浪费。
They'll never get anything in there.
他们永远不会得到任何东西。
I'm just wasting memory.
我只是在浪费记忆。
AUDIENCE: So if you could guarantee
观众：所以如果您可以保证
that your inputs would be evenly distributed--
您的输入将平均分配-
PROFESSOR: So if our inputs are random
教授：如果我们的输入是随机的
then the hash function-- most hash functions will
然后是哈希函数-大多数哈希函数会
do a good job of producing a random output.
做好产生随机输出的工作。
The problem is real life inputs are not random.
问题是现实生活中的输入不是随机的。
For example, if you get-- asides from this--
例如，如果您从中得到了帮助，
if you get data from a camera, so if you get your color pixels
如果您从相机获取数据，那么如果您获得了彩色像素
from a camera, then because of noise those
来自相机，然后由于噪音
might have the last few bits, always be the same thing.
可能只有最后几位，总是一样。
Also it seems like in real life-- [INAUDIBLE],
似乎在现实生活中[[听不清]，
in his book, argues about this.
在他的书中对此进行了争论。
It seems like in real life there are
在现实生活中似乎有
a lot of sequences that look like that, that would make
很多看起来像这样的序列
your hash function behave poorly.
您的哈希函数的行为不佳。
So again, the keyword is distribute.
同样，关键字是distributed。
If some non-random property in the input
如果在输入中有一些非随机属性
is reflected in the output, then that's a bad hash function.
反映在输出中，那么这是一个错误的哈希函数。
AUDIENCE: Would you gain a lot of time
听众：你会花很多时间吗
from your mod operation?
从你的mod操作？
Because in mod 2 to the n you just truncate any bits
因为在mod 2的n中，您只需要截断任何位
to the left of the n.
在n的左边
PROFESSOR: Yeah, so that's why we would do this, right?
教授：是的，这就是为什么我们要这样做，对吗？
That's why we're even considering this case.
这就是为什么我们甚至考虑这种情况。
AUDIENCE: Because that'd be really nice to be able to not--
听众：因为能够做到这一点真是太好了-
PROFESSOR: So modulo is faster, but in return my hash function
教授：所以取模更快，但是返回我的哈希函数
is crap here.
在这里胡扯。
So usually we prefer-- it turns out that in practice nicer hash
所以通常我们更喜欢-事实证明，在实践中更好的哈希
functions give better speed improvements overall.
功能总体上改善了速度。
So if you think of how a hash is laid out in memory,
因此，如果您考虑哈希在内存中的布局方式，
you'll see that because of caching.
您会因为缓存而看到它。
And everything gets better to take more time on the mod
一切都会变得更好，以便在mod上花费更多时间
function and use up all your memory for the hash table.
函数并用完所有的内存用于哈希表。
So this is why we don't use the and we use this.
因此，这就是为什么我们不使用而是使用它的原因。
Not because of this argument.
不是因为这种说法。
So a good question required a lot of talking and remembering
因此，一个好的问题需要大量的交谈和记忆
what's a good hash function, what's a bad hash function.
什么是好哈希函数，什么是坏哈希函数。
Thank you.
谢谢。
OK, let's look at the code a little bit.
好的，让我们看一下代码。
Everyone looked at it, right?
大家都看了吧？
So this time we have modules.
所以这次我们有模块。
We don't have everything in one big file.
我们没有将所有内容都放在一个大文件中。
Can someone tell me what are the modules we care about, and why?
有人可以告诉我我们关心的模块是什么，为什么？
AUDIENCE: The problem with the one's
听众：一个人的问题
we have to code ourselves.
我们必须自己编码。
PROFESSOR: OK, let's start with that.
教授：好的，让我们开始吧。
AUDIENCE: Sub-sequence hashes-- interval sub-sequence hashes.
听众：子序列散列-间隔子序列散列。
PROFESSOR: OK, so these are all in DNA seq, right?
教授：好的，所以这些都在DNA序列中，对吗？
So the module is-- so yeah, the PSET hopefully
所以模块是-是的，希望PSET
says that you need to upload this file because it's
说您需要上传此文件，因为它是
the only file you'll need to modify.
您唯一需要修改的文件。
So everything that we need to write is here.
因此，我们需要编写的所有内容都在这里。
Now pretty much everything that's in that file
现在，该文件中的几乎所有内容
needs to be modified.
需要修改。
So I'm not going to list them out.
所以我不会列出它们。
What else do we want to read in that PSET?
我们还想在该PSET中阅读什么？
AUDIENCE: Rolling [INAUDIBLE]
听众：滚动[听不清]
PROFESSOR: OK, where is rolling hash?
教授：好的，滚动哈希值在哪里？
AUDIENCE: In the [INAUDIBLE]
观众：在[听不清]
PROFESSOR: So what's different between the API in rolling hash
教授：那么滚动散列的API之间有什么不同
and the API that we talked about last time?
以及我们上次讨论的API？
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: Them having the [INAUDIBLE] pop,
观众：他们弹出[音频不清晰]，
or it would skip.
否则会跳过。
And that's something else [INAUDIBLE] just has a slide,
还有[音频不清晰]只是一张幻灯片，
it puts everything in one operation.
它将一切都放在一个操作中。
PROFESSOR: All right, so we have append and skip.
教授：好的，所以我们要追加和跳过。
And we built some beautiful code with that.
我们以此构建了一些漂亮的代码。
And we looked at some fancy math because of it.
因此，我们看了一些奇特的数学运算。
But it turns out that for this PSET
但事实证明，对于此PSET
we can get away with slide.
我们可以摆脱幻灯片。
And we started from slide and built these two methods
我们从幻灯片开始，构建了这两种方法
last time.
上次。
So I'm not going to explain slide again.
因此，我将不再解释幻灯片。
It's exactly what we had in the code
这正是我们在代码中所拥有的
before we started breaking them up.
在我们开始分解它们之前。
OK so this is the rolling hash.
确定，所以这是滚动哈希。
It is good.
很好
Do we care about anything else?
我们还关心其他吗？
AUDIENCE: I guess you can look at the rest of the code,
听众：我想您可以看一下其余的代码，
if you feel like it.
如果您喜欢的话。
PROFESSOR: You can look at the rest of the code
教授：您可以看一下其余的代码
if you feel like it, yep.
如果您愿意，是的。
So I highlighted one file that might be useful,
所以我强调了一个可能有用的文件，
and that's Kfasta.py.
那就是Kfasta.py。
That file has a FASTA sequence class,
该文件具有FASTA序列类，
and that's reads from a file and returns something.
从文件中读取并返回一些内容。
And the important thing is it doesn't return a list.
重要的是它不会返回列表。
If you remember the doc dists, doc dist 1 thorugh doc
如果您还记得doc dists，则doc dist 1 thorugh doc
dist 8 dot PI, fun times.
dist 8点PI，娱乐时间。
What we had there was we took the input file,
我们在那里得到的是输入文件，
and we read it all a list.
我们都阅读了清单。
This time we're not doing that.
这次我们不这样做。
We're writing, what, 20 lines of code instead of what
我们在写20行代码，而不是20行
could be five lines of code to read the input.
可能是五行代码来读取输入。
Why is that?
这是为什么？
AUDIENCE: Less memory?
听众：更少的内存？
PROFESSOR: Less memory, OK.
教授：减少内存，确定。
So if we're doing it this way, chances
因此，如果我们这样做，机会
are that if we tried to shove the whole input into memory,
就是如果我们试图将整个输入推入内存，
it wouldn't fit.
它不合适。
And it would crash and you would get 0
它会崩溃，您将得到0
on the test because of that.
因此，在测试中。
So that's not good.
所以那不好。
So what do we use instead?
那我们用什么代替呢？
Does anyone know what this thing is called?
有人知道这个东西叫什么吗？
What this class is called?
这个班叫什么？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
PROFESSOR: Iterator, very good.
教授：迭代器，非常好。
AUDIENCE: Why do they call it FASTA?
听众：他们为什么称其为FASTA？
Because it goes faster?
因为走得更快？
PROFESSOR: I think the letters are a bio acronym.
教授：我认为这些字母是生物的缩写。
AUDIENCE: Oh, OK.
听众：哦，好。
PROFESSOR: Does anyone, does anyone do bio here?
教授：有没有人在这里做生物？
I've seen that before.
我以前见过。
So it's a bio thing.
所以这是一个生物的东西。
Let's not worry about it.
不用担心。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
Or, your can use that for any type of file.
或者，您可以将其用于任何类型的文件。
Like, you don't have to use it just for bio files.
就像，您不必仅将其用于生物文件。
PROFESSOR: Well, presumably it's reads,
教授：好吧，大概是读
it takes advantage of the format that they're stored in,
它利用了它们存储的格式，
and gives you a list instead of something else.
并为您提供列表，而不是其他内容。
So how does an iterator work?
那么迭代器如何工作？
Suppose you're building your own iterator.
假设您正在构建自己的迭代器。
What do you have to implement?
您必须执行什么？
AUDIENCE: Iterator [INAUDIBLE]
听众：迭代器[听不清]
PROFESSOR: OK, let's start with next, that's the fun one.
教授：好的，让我们开始下一个，这很有趣。
What does next do?
接下来做什么？
AUDIENCE: It's like pop.
听众：就像流行音乐。
PROFESSOR: OK, so it's like pop in what way?
教授：好的，这就像流行音乐一样吗？
AUDIENCE: It gives you the next character.
听众：它给你下一个角色。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
And what happens when you're at the end of the list?
当您位于列表末尾时，会发生什么？
AUDIENCE: It stops.
听众：它停止了。
PROFESSOR: How do you stop?
教授：您如何停止？
AUDIENCE: It raises an exception?
听众：这引发了例外？
PROFESSOR: So next will either return an element,
教授：因此，下一步将返回一个元素，
that's the next element in the sequence
那是序列中的下一个元素
that you're iterating over.
您正在迭代。
Or it will raise a stop iteration exception
否则将引发停止迭代异常
error to stop iteration, cool.
错误停止迭代，很酷。
So what's the other method?
那么另一种方法是什么呢？
Someone said it before, say it again.
有人说过，再说一次。
AUDIENCE: Iter.
听众：Iter。
PROFESSOR: Iter.
教授：Iter。
What does this do in an iterator?
这在迭代器中有什么作用？
AUDIENCE: It returns itself.
听众：它返回自己。
PROFESSOR: All right, very good.
教授：好的，很好。
In an iterator this is how you will implement it all the time.
在迭代器中，这就是您始终将其实现的方式。
Does anyone know what's the point of iter?
有人知道迭代的意义吗？
AUDIENCE: So you can return an iterator?
听众：那么您可以返回一个迭代器？
Because that's what it told us to do in the PSET.
因为这就是它告诉我们在PSET中要做的事情。
PROFESSOR: OK, so iter returns and iterator.
教授：好的，所以iter返回并进行迭代。
But it doesn't-- you don't have to start from an iterator.
但这不是-您不必从迭代器开始。
You can start from any object.
您可以从任何对象开始。
And if it has a method iter, then it
如果它有方法迭代，那么它
should give you an iterator that iterates over that object.
应该给您一个迭代该对象的迭代器。
So if you have something like a list-- 1, 2, 3, 4-- then
因此，如果您有清单-1，2，3，4--
if you call iter on this, you'll get an iterator for it,
如果对此调用iter，则会得到一个迭代器，
hopefully, right?
希望是吧？
And this is what Python uses when you say for i in.
这就是Python在您对我说的时候所使用的。
So behind the scenes, whatever object you give it here,
因此，在幕后，无论您在此处提供什么对象，
gets an iter call.
接到一个迭代电话。
And then that produces an iterator.
然后产生一个迭代器。
And then Python calls next until stop iteration happens.
然后Python调用下一个，直到停止迭代发生。
So you can write an iterator that
所以你可以写一个迭代器
almost behaves like a list.
几乎像列表一样
You can use it in these [INAUDIBLE] instructions,
您可以在这些[音频不清晰]说明中使用它，
and it works as if it was a list,
它就像一个列表一样工作，
except it uses a lot less memory, because it computes
除了使用更少的内存外，因为它可以计算
the elements.
要素。
Hopefully every time next is called,
希望每次下一次被调用时，
you're computing the next element that you're returning.
您正在计算要返回的下一个元素。
If you're storing everything in a list then returning
如果您将所有内容存储在列表中，则返回
the elements that way, that's not the very smart iterator.
这样的元素，那不是很聪明的迭代器。
OK let's look at the last page.
好，让我们看看最后一页。
So the last page has an iterator on top.
因此，最后一页的顶部有一个迭代器。
And the iterator computes-- given a list,
然后迭代器计算-给定一个列表，
it computes the reverse of that list.
它计算该列表的反向。
And you can see that it doesn't reverse the list
您会发现它不会反转列表
and then keep the reversed list in memory.
然后将反向列表保留在内存中。
Instead, every time you call next,
相反，每次您下次打电话时，
it does some magic with the indexes--
它对索引有一些神奇作用-
I think the magic is called math--
我认为魔术叫做数学
and then it return something for as long as it can.
然后它会尽可能长地返回某些内容。
So this is how you implement reverse
所以这就是实现反向的方式
without producing a new list.
而不生成新列表。
If the original list was order, say had n elements, then
如果原始列表是有序的，说有n个元素，则
if you'd produce a new list, you'd consume order and memory.
如果要生成新列表，则会消耗订单和内存。
This think consumes order 1 memory,
这个想法消耗了1阶内存，
and the running time is the same, asymptotically.
渐近地，运行时间是相同的
OK, any question on iterators?
好的，关于迭代器有什么问题吗？
AUDIENCE: So it's going from the very end,
听众：从一开始，
oh, to the very beginning, and then it's stepping back.
哦，从一开始，然后就退一步了。
PROFESSOR: So reverse, if I give it
教授：那么，相反，如果我给它
the list 1, 2, 3, 4, I want reverse to give it back 4, 3,
清单1、2、3、4，我想反向将其归还4、3，
2, 1.
2、1
Except it's not going to return a list,
除非它不会返回列表，
it's going to return something that I can use here.
它会返回一些我可以在这里使用的东西。
AUDIENCE: Mm hm, ah, OK.
听众：嗯，嗯，好。
PROFESSOR: OK, yes.
教授：好的，是的。
AUDIENCE: Is it ever possible to, sort of,
听众：有没有可能，
rewind the iterator to like, sort of, reset it?
将迭代器倒回喜欢的位置，将其重置？
PROFESSOR: OK, is it?
教授：好吗？
AUDIENCE: No.
听众：不。
PROFESSOR: Nope.
教授：不。
So Python iterators are simple.
因此，Python迭代器很简单。
All you can do is go forward.
您所能做的就是继续前进。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
PROFESSOR: The reason that is good is
教授：好的原因是
because you can use them for streams.
因为您可以将它们用于流。
So if you get data from a file, or if you can get data
因此，如果您从文件中获取数据，或者可以获取数据
from the network, you can wrap it in an iterator.
从网络上，您可以将其包装在迭代器中。
If you wanted to support resume on data that you
如果您想支持对您的数据的恢复
get from the network, you'd have to buffer all the data.
从网络上获取数据，您将不得不缓冲所有数据。
AUDIENCE: So you would have to call
听众：所以你必须打电话
the iter about that again and--
再次对此进行迭代-
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
Yeah, if you want to rewind, get another iterator.
是的，如果您想倒带，请使用另一个迭代器。
OK, that's a good question, thank you.
好的，这是一个很好的问题，谢谢。
So these are iterators.
所以这些是迭代器。
Now we're going to go over some Python magic, which
现在，我们将介绍一些Python魔术，
is called generators.
被称为发电机。
So look at the iterator code, and then look
所以看一下迭代器代码，然后看
at the equivalent code right below it.
在它下面的等效代码处。
So 12 lines of Python turned into three lines of Python
所以12行Python变成了3行Python
that do exactly the same thing.
做完全一样的事情。
So the reverse method will return an object
所以反向方法将返回一个对象
that is an iterator, and that you can use just
那是一个迭代器，您可以只使用
like the iterator in the reverse class.
像反向类中的迭代器一样。
Do people understand what that code does?
人们是否了解该代码的作用？
If you do I'm so out of here, we're done.
如果您愿意，我会不在这里，我们就完成了。
AUDIENCE: What does yield do?
听众：产量有什么作用？
PROFESSOR: What does yield do?
教授：产量有什么作用？
All right, that's the hard question, what does yield do?
好吧，这是一个难题，产量是做什么的？
I will probably spend the rest of the session on the answer
我可能会把剩下的时间都花在答案上
to that question.
这个问题。
You're asking all the had questions today, man.
你今天要问所有的问题，伙计。
So yield, does anyone know conceptually what yield does?
那么，收益率，从概念上讲，有人知道吗？
Not in detail, just what's it supposed
没有详细说明，这是什么意思
to do so that the rest of the code works?
这样做以便其余的代码都能正常工作？
Yes.
是。
AUDIENCE: If you're driving someplace
观众：如果您开车去某个地方
and there's a yield sign, you pause.
而且有一个屈服信号，你停下来。
PROFESSOR: OK, Python yield.
教授：好的，Python的产量。
So I like the word pause in there.
所以我喜欢其中停顿这个词。
The word pause is useful.
暂停一词很有用。
So say, instead of implementing this,
可以这么说，而不是实施
say we're implementing sub-sequence hashes.
说我们正在实现子序列哈希。
AUDIENCE: It kind of spit something out, but keeps going.
听众：有点吐出来，但是还在继续。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: Returns [INAUDIBLE]
听众：返回[听不清]
PROFESSOR: OK, so suppose you're implementing
教授：好的，假设您正在实施
sub-sequence hashes.
子序列哈希。
What's the worst, worst possible way you could implement this?
实施此方法的最糟糕的方法是什么？
AUDIENCE: Return a list.
听众：返回列表。
PROFESSOR: OK, so the worst, worst way is to go all the way,
教授：好的，所以最糟糕，最糟糕的方法就是一路走下去，
brute force, don't use the rolling hashes,
蛮力，不要使用滚动哈希，
don't use anything.
不要使用任何东西。
The next best way is to make a list, right?
下一个最佳方法是列出清单，对吧？
So you're going to start with an empty list.
因此，您将从一个空列表开始。
Then you're going to use the rolling hash in some way.
然后，您将以某种方式使用滚动哈希。
And in some loop you're going to say list.append e.
在某些循环中，您将说list.append e。
And then you're going to return the list.
然后您将返回列表。
Does this makes sense?
这有意义吗？
OK, what's the problem with this code?
好的，这段代码有什么问题？
AUDIENCE: You're going to have a huge list.
听众：您将有一个庞大的清单。
PROFESSOR: Going to have a huge list.
教授：将会有一个庞大的清单。
So the way we fix it with iterators is we remove this,
因此，我们使用迭代器对其进行修复的方法是将其删除，
we replace this with yield e, and we remove this.
我们将其替换为yield e，然后将其删除。
And now it's a generator.
现在它是一个发电机。
And now this consumes a constant amount of memory,
现在，这消耗了恒定数量的内存，
instead of building a list.
而不是建立清单。
And as long as you only want an iterator out of this method,
而且只要您只希望使用此方法中的迭代器，
you'll get the right thing.
你会得到正确的事情。
Your code will still work in exactly the same way.
您的代码仍将以完全相同的方式工作。
OK, so the big question is what does this guy do, right?
好吧，所以最大的问题是这个人做什么，对吗？
This is where the magic is.
这就是魔术所在。
So I already said, as a first hint,
所以我已经说过，作为第一个提示，
that this guy will return an iterator.
这个家伙将返回一个迭代器。
So can someone try to imagine their Python, and see this?
那么有人可以想象一下他们的Python，然后看看吗？
So suppose it's your Python, you see this.
因此，假设这是您的Python，您会看到。
What do you do?
你是做什么？
AUDIENCE: You wait for some sort of command of some sort, right?
听众：您在等待某种命令，对吗？
PROFESSOR: No, let's try something else.
教授：不，我们再尝试其他方法。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
PROFESSOR: So the execution of this pauses.
教授：因此，该执行暂停。
What happens?
怎么了？
So we're looping somewhere, we got a yield.
因此，我们在某个地方循环，我们获得了收益。
We stop, what's the first thing we do?
我们停下来，我们要做的第一件事是什么？
AUDIENCE: Spit out e.
听众：吐出e。
PROFESSOR: So you're saying you return e from this guy?
教授：所以您是说您从这个人那里归还e？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] out e [INAUDIBLE]
听众：[听不清] e [听不清]
PROFESSOR: So I want to return something--
教授：所以我想退货-
I want to return something else from this.
我想从中返回其他内容。
So I want to use this as if it was a list, yes?
所以我想像使用列表一样使用它，是吗？
AUDIENCE: We store e somewhere.
听众：我们将e存储在某个地方。
PROFESSOR: OK, store e somewhere.
教授：好的，将e存储在某个地方。
AUDIENCE: Do you return the pointer of e?
听众：您是否返回e的指针？
PROFESSOR: Almost, so there's a word for the object
教授：差不多了，这个对象有一个字
that I'm returning.
我回来了
So I want to use it as if it was a list.
所以我想像使用列表一样使用它。
So I want to pretend that I had returned list in this method,
所以我想假装我已经用这种方法返回了列表，
right?
对？
So what's the closest thing to a list that I can return.
那么，最接近我可以返回的列表的是什么。
AUDIENCE: An iterator.
听众：一个迭代器。
PROFESSOR: An iterator, thank you, all right.
教授：一个迭代器，谢谢。
So we will grab some information from here.
因此，我们将从此处获取一些信息。
We'll put it in a nice box.
我们将其放入一个漂亮的盒子中。
And that box will behave like an iterator.
该框的行为类似于迭代器。
OK, so the first thing, someone said put e away,
好，所以第一件事就是有人说把e收起来，
so that's when we call next we're going to spit that out.
因此，当我们接下来打电话时，我们将把它吐出来。
What else do I need to put away?
我还需要收拾些什么？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
PROFESSOR: Yep, so this is a lot of magic.
教授：是的，所以这很神奇。
This tiny box actually has a lot of magic in it.
这个小盒子里面确实有很多魔力。
Because when I call next, I want to get e.
因为当我下次打电话时，我想得到e。
But I want to come back here and keep going, right?
但是我想回到这里继续前进，对吗？
So I have my code that's using the iterator.
所以我的代码正在使用迭代器。
And there's this code here, that's sort of
这里有这段代码，
in a frozen state.
处于冻结状态。
Did you guys see any movies where people are frozen up
你们有看过冻结人的电影吗
and then, in the future, they're unfrozen
然后，在未来，它们将被冻结
and they start moving again?
然后他们又开始移动了？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] movies.
观众：[听不清]电影。
PROFESSOR: All right, cool.
教授：好的，很酷。
So this is like that, this takes up the whole function,
这样就占据了整个功能，
freezes it up and puts it in a box here.
将其冻结并将其放在此处的框中。
And it returns an iterator that can use the box in the future.
并且它返回一个迭代器，该迭代器将来可以使用该框。
So when you call next, it gives e,
因此，当您下次致电时，它会给出e，
which is the guy that you put in here.
你在这里放的那个人
And then it take the function out of the box,
然后将功能直接使用
unfreezes it, and lets it run again
解冻它，然后再次运行
until it hits yield again.
直到再次达到产量。
Then what happens the next time it hits yield?
那么，下一次达到收益率时会发生什么呢？
So, you're looping, and you're yielding again.
因此，您循环播放，并且再次屈服。
And say this time you're yielding.
并说这次你屈服。
AUDIENCE: Just do the same thing?
听众：做同样的事情吗？
AUDIENCE: Do you put it in that iterator?
听众：你把它放在那个迭代器中吗？
Or do you make another iterator?
还是要制作另一个迭代器？
PROFESSOR: Same iterator.
教授：相同的迭代器。
So while this is looping, the code outside
所以当这循环时，外面的代码
should get the values that it's yielding.
应该得到它产生的值。
So this has to behave as one iterator.
因此，它必须充当一个迭代器。
So the code is unfrozen, it's allowed
所以代码是未冻结的，它被允许
to execute until it says yield again.
执行直到再次说出yield为止。
And then it says yield with a new element.
然后用新元素表示收益。
I put this guy in the box.
我把这个家伙放在盒子里。
Then I return the old guy as the return value for next.
然后，我将老家伙返回作为下一个的返回值。
AUDIENCE: Oh.
听众：哦。
PROFESSOR: And then it's frozen again.
教授：然后又被冻结了。
So this guy's still in a frozen state.
因此，这个人仍然处于冻结状态。
In the movies, I think you're only unfrozen once.
在电影中，我认为您只冻结了一次。
And then you keep going, right?
然后您继续前进，对吗？
And there's a happy ending.
有一个幸福的结局。
Where here, every time you call yield
在这里，每次调用收益率
you're frozen again, until someone calls next.
您再次被冻结，直到有人打电话给下一个。
Does this make sense?
这有意义吗？
AUDIENCE: It's kind of like Groundhog Day.
听众：有点像土拨鼠日。
PROFESSOR: Yes, except you're allowed to go forward.
教授：是的，除了您可以前进。
So this keeps going forward.
因此，这一直在继续。
AUDIENCE: --up, thought.
听众：-起来，想一想。
So it's looping.
因此，它正在循环。
It's the same day, really.
真的是同一天。
It's doing different things, though.
不过，它在做不同的事情。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
But all your state is saved.
但是您的所有状态都已保存。
So there, some of the state is rolled back.
因此，某些状态会回滚。
Here all the state is saved.
此处保存了所有状态。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
PROFESSOR: OK, but if that analogy helps, keep it.
教授：好的，但是如果这样的比喻有帮助，请保留。
AUDIENCE: When you call next, are you computing e
听众：下次打电话时，您正在计算e
or e prime to be returned?
还是要退货的素数？
PROFESSOR: So when you're calling next,
教授：所以，当您接下来打电话时，
you're computing e prime and returning e.
您正在计算e素数并返回e。
AUDIENCE: So the value you get from next is pre-computed?
听众：那么从下一个获得的价值是预先计算的？
PROFESSOR: So the value you get form next is
教授：那么您接下来获得的价值是
what you yielded before.
你以前屈服的
AUDIENCE: Wait, so you would just take some sequence hashes
听众：等等，所以您只需要进行一些序列散列
instance of that, and then just by putting in yield,
实例，然后通过增加收益，
now it's magically become an iterator
现在它神奇地变成了迭代器
and you can call that next on it?
你可以打电话给下一个吗？
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
And inside, you don't have to know that it's an iterator.
在内部，您不必知道它是一个迭代器。
So you don't have a method next here, right?
所以，您这里接下来没有方法了，对吧？
I don't implement next or iter here.
我在这里不执行下一步或迭代。
I write this as if it's printing stuff to the output.
我将其写为好像将内容打印到输出中。
You can think of yield is a print.
您可以认为产量是印刷品。
If you wanted an iterator, then pretend
如果您想要一个迭代器，那么假装
you're printing what you want to iterate over.
您正在打印要迭代的内容。
And instead of saying print you say yield.
与其说打印，不如说产量。
And then you use that.
然后您使用它。
OK, now what happens when we're done?
好，现在完成后会发生什么？
What happens when this loop is done
完成此循环后会发生什么
and you return from this method?
然后您从此方法返回？
We said there's no return value.
我们说没有返回值。
AUDIENCE: It raises a stop?
听众：停下来了吗？
PROFESSOR: So when we return, it's
教授：所以当我们回来时，
going to keep in-- have to remember that it's done, right?
要坚持下去-必须记住它已经完成了，对吧？
And the first time, it has some element here
第一次，这里有一些元素
that it has to return.
它必须返回。
So every time you call yield we put a new element in the box,
因此，每次您调用yield时，我们都会在框中输入一个新元素，
and return the old one.
并退还旧的。
So now we would return the old one.
所以现在我们将退回旧的。
We've returned e prime, take it out, and put done in the box.
我们已退回e prime，将其取出，然后放入盒子中。
So in the future, if next is called again,
因此，将来如果再次调用next，
raise stop iteration.
提高停止迭代。
No more freezing, unfreezing, because we're done.
不再冻结，解冻，因为我们完成了。
We're returned.
我们回来了。
AUDIENCE: So if you called next it would just give you nothing?
听众：那么，如果您接下来打电话给您，它什么也不会给您？
PROFESSOR: It has to raise this exception.
教授：必须提出这个例外。
AUDIENCE: So you mean, like-- oh, so it-- oh, I see.
听众：所以你的意思是-哦，是这样-哦，我明白了。
It would give you red text then?
那会给你红色的文字吗？
PROFESSOR: If you called it directly, yes,
教授：如果您直接致电，是的，
it would give you red text.
它会给您红色文字。
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: So this takes a sequence or a list,
听众：这需要一个序列或一个列表，
not another iterator, ever?
从来没有另一个迭代器？
PROFESSOR: This?
教授：这吗？
What's this?
这是什么？
This other code here?
这是其他代码吗？
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: Not necessarily.
教授：不一定。
AUDIENCE: Or you could give it a procedure.
听众：或者你可以给它一个程序。
PROFESSOR: I can give it an iterator
教授：我可以给它一个迭代器
if I'm iterating over it using for-in.
如果我使用for-in遍历它。
AUDIENCE: Like, for something in one iterator, yield
听众：例如，对于一个迭代器中的某项，收益
that something, and then [INAUDIBLE]
那东西，然后[听不清]
AUDIENCE: Oh, OK.
听众：哦，好。
PROFESSOR: Yeah, that's a good point.
教授：是的，这很重要。
I'll get to that later, when we talk
等一下再说
about how we're going to solve the PSET.
关于我们如何解决PSET的问题。
No, we're not solving the PSET for you.
不，我们没有为您解决PSET。
But we'll talk about it a little bit.
但是，我们将稍作讨论。
But yeah, that's a good point.
但是，是的，这很不错。
So there's no reason why you can't
所以没有理由你不能
have an argument here that, either a list or an iterator,
这里有一个参数，即列表或迭代器，
and then you're iterating over it.
然后您要遍历它。
And then you have nested generators.
然后您有嵌套的生成器。
So you have generators returned in other generators,
所以您有其他发电机返回的发电机，
and you have a whole chain of things
而且你有一连串的事情
happening when you say next.
接下来说的话会发生。
AUDIENCE: Wait, so this is a generator then,
听众：等等，那么这就是发电机，
because it produces-- well it is an iterator though?
因为它产生了-虽然它是一个迭代器？
PROFESSOR: So a generator returns an iterator
教授：因此，生成器返回迭代器
from this method.
从这种方法。
So a generator acts like an iterator,
因此，生成器的作用类似于迭代器，
except when you call next, it unfreezes this code here,
除了下次调用时，它会在此处解冻此代码，
and it let's it run.
它开始运行。
AUDIENCE: But I mean, it's basically an iterator then?
听众：但是我的意思是，那基本上是一个迭代器？
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: But we're just calling it a generator because--
听众：但是我们之所以称其为发电机是因为-
PROFESSOR: Because there's a lot more magic.
教授：因为还有很多魔术。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
PROFESSOR: So an iterator just says next and iter.
教授：因此，一个迭代器只说下一个然后迭代。
This is all that an iterator is, nothing more.
这就是迭代器的全部，仅此而已。
Any object that has these two methods is an iterator.
具有这两种方法的任何对象都是迭代器。
AUDIENCE: Oh, OK.
听众：哦，好。
PROFESSOR: Now a generator is a piece of Python magic
教授：现在，生成器是Python的魔力
that let's you write shorter iterators.
让我们编写更短的迭代器。
So three lines, as opposed to 13 lines.
所以三行，而不是十三行。
And we came up with a way to turn
我们想出了一种方法
in a code that would build a list,
在可以建立清单的程式码中
and easily turn it into a code that uses a generator,
并轻松地将其转换为使用生成器的代码，
and that uses constant memory instead of building that list.
并且使用常量内存而不是建立该列表。
AUDIENCE: OK, now I know how an iterator functions.
听众：好的，现在我知道迭代器的功能了。
PROFESSOR: Exactly.
教授：是的。
OK, do generators make sense now?
好了，发电机现在有意义吗？
Yes.
是。
AUDIENCE: If you wanted to loop through all
听众：如果您想遍历所有
of the values in a generator, do you just
生成器中的值，您只是
wait until the exception's raised?
等到引发异常？
Or should you, like, keep track of how many things
还是您应该跟踪多少东西
are going to be in that generator?
将在那个发电机？
PROFESSOR: So, when you have a generator,
教授：所以，当您有发电机时，
you'd have no idea how many things there are.
你不知道有多少东西。
That's a good point.
那是个很好的观点。
So you're wondering if I have an iterator, say any iterator,
所以您想知道我是否有一个迭代器，比如说任何迭代器，
not necessarily a generator, how do I know how many things it's
不一定是发电机，我怎么知道它有多少东西
going to return, right?
要回来了吧？
Do I have ln?
我有ln吗？
I do not have ln.
我没有ln。
So an iterator does not have ln.
因此，迭代器没有ln。
So you have to iterate through it.
因此，您必须遍历它。
And most importantly, some iterators can never return.
最重要的是，某些迭代器永远不会返回。
So you can have an iterator that streams data for you
因此，您可以拥有一个可以为您流数据的迭代器
across the network.
跨网络。
Or you can have an iterator that iterates over the Fibonacci
或者您可以有一个迭代斐波纳契的迭代器
numbers.
数字。
That's an infinite sequence, right?
那是一个无限的顺序，对吧？
It's never going to end.
它永远不会结束。
So ln would not even be defined then.
因此，ln甚至都不会被定义。
Good question, I like it.
好问题，我喜欢。
AUDIENCE: Is there an is-next method for either iterators
听众：两个迭代器是否都有一个is-next方法
or generators?
还是发电机？
PROFESSOR: Nope.
教授：不。
This is what you get, if there is no in.
如果没有，这就是您得到的。
AUDIENCE: If that is mature then--
听众：如果那很成熟，
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
So in Java you have this belief that you
因此，在Java中，您有这样的信念：
shouldn't get exceptions.
不应该例外。
You should be able to check for them, right?
您应该可以检查它们，对吗？
So maybe that's why you're asking.
所以也许这就是为什么你问。
So if people coming from Java know that any time a method
因此，如果来自Java的人们随时知道一种方法
raises an exception, there should
引发异常，应该
be another method that tells you whether this first method is
可以告诉您第一个方法是否是
going to raise an exception or not.
是否会引发例外。
In Python the exception is just raised.
在Python中，仅引发了异常。
So exceptions are not a lot more expensive
因此，异常的代价并不昂贵
than regular instructions, because we're
比常规说明要多，因为我们
using an interpreted language, and it's already
使用一种解释语言，它已经
reasonably slow.
相当慢。
So it can do exceptions for free, yay.
所以它可以免费做例外，是的。
So this is how it works.
这就是它的工作方式。
This is how for-in works.
这是for-in的工作方式。
Every time you do a for-in, an exception is raised.
每次您进行for-in时，都会引发异常。
AUDIENCE: We don't have to catch that, then?
听众：那我们不必得意吗？
PROFESSOR: Nope, the for-in catches it for you.
教授：不会，for-in为您服务。
AUDIENCE: That's tricky stuff.
听众：这很棘手。
PROFESSOR: But it's nice because then you
教授：那很好，因为那时候你
can build any iterator that acts like a list.
可以构建任何类似于列表的迭代器。
And then you can do even more fancy stuff,
然后您可以做更多花哨的事情，
and build a generator.
并建造一个发电机。
And you're using constant memory instead of order and memory
而且您使用的是恒定内存，而不是顺序和内存
for producing an order and size list.
用于生成订单和尺寸列表。
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: So if we get passed in an iterator
观众：所以如果我们通过迭代器
and then just yielded what we passed in, yielded
然后就产生了我们传承的东西
the iterator, would that just, essentially,
迭代器，从本质上讲，
delay everything by one?
推迟一切吗？
PROFESSOR: So you're yielding the iterator as next, right?
教授：因此，您接下来要产生迭代器，对吗？
AUDIENCE: What?
听众：什么？
Yeah.
是的
PROFESSOR: You want to yield the iterator as next.
教授：您想像下面那样产生迭代器。
Because if you yield the iterator object,
因为如果产生迭代器对象，
you're going to return that object every time.
您将每次都返回该对象。
So you're thinking of something that--
所以您在想一些事情-
AUDIENCE: So you need to increase--
听众：所以你需要增加-
PROFESSOR: You'll yield up next, right?
教授：接下来，您会屈服吧？
AUDIENCE: Right.
听众：对。
PROFESSOR: You can have a method that says this is the method.
教授：您可以使用一个方法来说明此方法。
And then you take in an iterator.
然后加入一个迭代器。
And then you yield it up next.
然后您将其屈服。
But then you'll, basically, get the same thing.
但是，基本上，您将获得相同的结果。
AUDIENCE: The same thing.
听众：同一件事。
But is it delayed by one or no?
但是它延迟了一个还是没有？
PROFESSOR: Nope.
教授：不。
No, so you have to work through this
不，所以你必须通过这个工作
to convince yourself that it's not delayed.
让自己相信它没有延迟。
So if it would be delayed by one,
因此，如果将其延迟一倍，
what's the first thing that you're yielding.
您要产生的第一件事是什么。
AUDIENCE: I don't know.
听众：我不知道。
PROFESSOR: Yeah, so no delay.
教授：是的，所以不要拖延。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
PROFESSOR: OK, cool.
教授：好的，很酷。
So let's see, what do we have to implement
让我们来看看，我们必须实现什么
in DNA seq, sub-sequence hashes.
在DNA序列中，子序列哈希。
Do people have an idea of how to implement that now?
人们是否有想法现在如何实施？
Yes?
是？
Does it make sense for everyone?
这对每个人有意义吗？
So you build it as if you were building a list,
因此，您就像在构建列表一样构建它，
and then you use yield to make it fast.
然后使用yield使其快速。
And by fast I mean less memory.
快速是指更少的内存。
OK, how about interval sub-sequence hashes?
好吧，区间子序列哈希如何？
The one below.
下面的一个。
AUDIENCE: Is that just like rolling hash,
听众：就像滚动哈希一样，
except you, like, have a step in your range?
除了您之外，您需要在自己的范围内迈出一步？
PROFESSOR: OK, so it's like having a step in your range.
教授：好的，这就像在您的范围内迈出了一步。
So how can you do that?
那你该怎么做呢？
What's one way of doing it?
这样做的一种方式是什么？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] hashes?
听众：[听不清]哈希？
PROFESSOR: Did anyone solve the PSET yet?
教授：有人解决过PSET吗？
Yes, OK how did you guys do it?
是的，你们是如何做到的？
Wait, no.
等一下
That's a bad question because you guys can answer too much.
这是一个不好的问题，因为你们可以回答太多。
So interval sub-sequence hashes versus sub-sequence hashes.
因此，区间子序列哈希与子序列哈希。
Did you copy paste the code?
您复制粘贴代码了吗？
AUDIENCE: Absolutely.
听众：绝对。
PROFESSOR: OK, so one way of doing it is copy
教授：好的，所以做到这一点的一种方法是复制
and pasting the code.
并粘贴代码。
The problem if you copy paste the code is then you're
如果您复制粘贴代码的问题是
not DRY.
不干。
There's this engineering thing-- DRY means do not
有一个工程学的东西-DRY意味着不要
repeat yourself.
再说一遍。
So if you're not DRY, if you copy paste,
因此，如果您不干燥，如果您复制粘贴，
then suppose you find the bug later.
然后假设您稍后找到该错误。
Suppose you run the big test and it crashes somewhere.
假设您运行了大型测试，并且崩溃了。
And you fix a bug in sub-sequence hashes.
并且您修复了子序列哈希中的一个错误。
AUDIENCE: Oh, we're supposed to, like,
听众：哦，我们应该，
call sub-sequence hashes from interval sub-sequence hashes,
从区间子序列哈希中调用子序列哈希，
right?
对？
PROFESSOR: That's another way of doing it that is DRY.
教授：那是干的另一种方式。
So this way you're not copy pasting the code.
因此，您无需复制粘贴代码。
AUDIENCE: We're inlining the code.
听众：我们正在内联代码。
PROFESSOR: You're inlining it manually, right?
教授：您是手动进行内联，对吗？
All right.
好吧。
So the problem, if you do this on a large scale,
所以问题是，如果您大规模进行此操作，
like when you go work somewhere, is
就像当你去某个地方工作时
that you end up with 20 copies of the same code.
最终得到20个相同代码的副本。
And then five of them have bug fixes and the other 15
然后其中五个修复了错误，另外15个修复了错误
don't, because people forgot where they are.
不会，因为人们忘记了他们在哪里。
So ideally, try to keep your code DRY.
因此，理想情况下，请尝试使代码保持DRY。
AUDIENCE: So, basically, a list of tuples, right?
听众：所以，基本上，有一个元组列表，对吗？
PROFESSOR: OK, so a list of tuples.
教授：好的，所以有一个元组列表。
What does a tuple have?
元组有什么？
AUDIENCE: The index at which the sub-sequence operates?
观众：子序列的运行索引？
PROFESSOR: So two indexes, right?
教授：那么有两个索引吧？
The index in the first sub-sequence, say--
第一个子序列中的索引说：
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
PROFESSOR: OK, say i1 and then the index in a second sequence,
教授：好的，先说i1，然后再说第二个索引，
for the same sub-sequence, r right?
对于相同的子序列，r对吗？
And then i1, i2 prime, i1, i2 second, so on and so forth.
然后是i1，i2质数，i1，i2秒，依此类推。
So you have the same sub-sequence
所以你有相同的子序列
in the first sequence matches more things in the second one.
在第一个序列中匹配第二个中的更多事物。
This is how you're supposed to return them.
这就是您应该退还它们的方式。
AUDIENCE: Does the order matter?
听众：顺序重要吗？
PROFESSOR: I hope not.
教授：我希望不会。
OK, any questions on this?
好，对此有任何疑问吗？
We went through generators fast.
我们快速通过了发电机。
You guys are smart.
你们很聪明。
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: Can you explain how the imaging works?
听众：您能解释一下成像的工作原理吗？
Like, how they create the [INAUDIBLE] on tuples.
就像他们如何在元组上创建[音频不清晰]。
PROFESSOR: No.
教授：不。
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
PROFESSOR: Sorry, I do not know.
教授：对不起，我不知道。
AUDIENCE: Wait, which part?
听众：等等，哪一部分？
AUDIENCE: So we yield the tuples.
听众：所以我们产生元组。
But I don't really get how they come up with the image from it.
但是我真的不了解他们如何从中得出图像。
AUDIENCE: From the tuples?
听众：来自元组？
Oh, I mean, I guess they're probably values.
哦，我是说，我想它们可能是价值观。
AUDIENCE: Yeah, because I thought
听众：是的，因为我想
if you compared two strings of DNA that had the exact same,
如果您比较两串完全相同的DNA，
I thought it would be like a diagonal line down,
我以为这就像一条对角线，
not just a small black box.
不只是一个小黑匣子。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
AUDIENCE: So I don't think I'm understanding
听众：所以我不认为我在理解
how they, like, image it.
他们如何形象化。
PROFESSOR: So you're supposed to get--
教授：所以你应该得到-
your image has some things here, and a match
您的图片有一些东西，还有一个匹配项
is going to give you a big diagonal line that's
会给你一条很大的对角线
stronger than everything else, right?
比其他任何东西都强，对吗？
AUDIENCE: It's really fanned out.
听众：真的散开了。
PROFESSOR: Well I don't have thin chalk.
教授：嗯，我没有粉笔。
AUDIENCE: No, no, there's like one really dark black box,
听众：不，不，有一个非常黑的盒子，
that's like really black.
那真的很黑。
So I thought that meant that all the tuples are there,
所以我认为这意味着所有元组都在那里，
and everything else is just kind of gray.
其他的一切都是灰色的。
PROFESSOR: Good question.
教授：好问题。
I will have to think about that--
我将不得不考虑-
AUDIENCE: --supposed to be there.
听众：-应该在那儿。
Is it like a notation thing, or--
就像记谱法一样吗？
PROFESSOR: I think that black box is supposed to be there.
教授：我认为应该有黑匣子。
Did anyone try comparing two things that
有没有人尝试比较两件事
shouldn't match, like the dog and the monkey?
不应该像狗和猴子一样搭配吗？
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
And the entire thing was like dark.
整个事情就像黑暗。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: --against, like, two same DNAs everything
听众：-就像两个相同的DNA一样
was very light.
很轻。
And there was like a very, very light gray line.
那里有一条非常非常浅的灰色线条。
But I thought that would be like black.
但是我认为那会像黑色。
PROFESSOR: So I think how black it is means
教授：所以我认为它有多黑
relative to all the sub-sequences, how long it is--
相对于所有子序列，要多长时间-
how long the sub-sequence you're recording is.
您正在录制的子序列多长时间。
Either that or how many.
无论是多少。
There is a function somewhere in there
那里有一个功能
that computes the intensity of a pixel, that's
计算像素的强度，即
square root of order 4 of something.
4阶的平方根。
OK, and I can look at that now and tell you.
好的，我现在可以看看并告诉您。
AUDIENCE: It's OK.
听众：可以。
It's not super important.
这不是超级重要。
PROFESSOR: Or we can talk about amortized analysis for a bit.
教授：或者我们可以谈谈摊销分析。
Yay!
好极了！
Let's talk about amortized analysis.
让我们谈谈摊销分析。
So this is what you're supposed to get, that's what matters.
这就是您应该得到的，这才是重要的。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
PROFESSOR: OK, so amortized analysis,
教授：好的，摊销分析，
what's the example that we talked about in class?
我们在课堂上谈论的例子是什么？
AUDIENCE: It's like list expansion?
听众：就像列表扩展吗？
PROFESSOR: OK, so you have-- you have a list.
教授：好的，所以您有一个清单。
And we know that the list is stored as an array, right?
而且我们知道列表存储为数组，对吗？
So this means that you can do indexing in constant time.
因此，这意味着您可以在恒定时间内进行索引。
So if you want to get the first element, order 1.
因此，如果要获取第一个元素，请订购1。
If you want to get the millionth element, order 1.
如果要获得百万分之一的元素，请订购1。
This is not true if you had a link list instead.
如果您有一个链接列表，则不正确。
The millionth element would be order a million.
第百万个元素将是一百万。
So this is an array.
所以这是一个数组。
What do we implement?
我们执行什么？
What's the operation that we implement on this list?
我们在此列表上执行的操作是什么？
AUDIENCE: Insert--
观众：插入-
PROFESSOR: Insert, append, push.
教授：插入，追加，推送。
Let's go for append, because that's what Python calls it.
让我们进行附加操作，因为这就是Python所说的。
OK, so append puts an element at the end of the list, right?
好的，所以append将元素放在列表的末尾，对吗？
So how does append work?
那么追加如何工作？
AUDIENCE: The array is not full.
听众：阵列未满。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So say I have some count variable here.
所以说我这里有一些计数变量。
So if the length of the array is bigger than count
因此，如果数组的长度大于count
then what do I do?
那我该怎么办？
AUDIENCE: Then we can directly insert.
听众：然后我们可以直接插入。
And because we're looking up in an array
而且因为我们要查找数组
and we're doing constant time.
而且我们正在做固定的时间。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
AUDIENCE: And so an order amount of information
听众：所以订购的信息量
in x [INAUDIBLE]?
在[[听不清]]中？
PROFESSOR: Sorry?
教授：对不起？
AUDIENCE: Order amount of information of x [INAUDIBLE]?
听众：订单信息量x [听不清]？
Or do we just--
还是我们只是-
PROFESSOR: Let's say this is our reference,
教授：可以说这是我们的参考，
so it's constant time.
所以这是恒定的时间。
AUDIENCE: Otherwise we don't have enough room in our array.
听众：否则我们的阵列空间不足。
So we need to make it bigger.
因此，我们需要使其更大。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So we have array 2 becomes new array
所以我们将数组2变成了新数组
of size 2 times count, right?
大小的2倍算吧？
Copy everything from--
复制所有内容-
AUDIENCE: --length of the array.
听众：-数组的长度。
I guess they're the same.
我想他们是一样的。
PROFESSOR: I hope they're the same.
教授：我希望他们是一样的。
AUDIENCE: It is.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: Yeah, I'd say that.
教授：是的，我这么说。
So copy from array to-- let's do this-- to array 2.
因此，从数组复制到-让我们这样做-复制到数组2。
And then array 2 becomes array.
然后数组2变成数组。
And then this code here goes here, right?
然后这段代码在这里，对吗？
So there's a better way to write this if statement
因此，有一种更好的方式编写此if语句
so the code isn't duplicated.
因此代码不会重复。
OK, so if the length is bigger than how many elements I have,
好，所以如果长度大于我拥有的元素数，
if I still have room in the array, what's the cost?
如果阵列中还有空间，那要花多少钱？
What's the running time?
几点钟了？
Constant.
不变。
Oh, let's put it on the left.
哦，把它放在左边。
OK, if I have to resize the array, what's the cost?
好吧，如果我必须调整数组的大小，那要花多少钱？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
PROFESSOR: So, if I did an operations, what then, right?
教授：那么，如果我做了手术，那是什么呢？
N is the size of the array.
N是数组的大小。
If the only operation I have is append,
如果我唯一的操作是追加，
then I can say n operations will cause
那我可以说n次操作会导致
the array of grow to size n.
增长到大小n的数组。
So n where n is the number of operations.
因此，n是操作数。
AUDIENCE: You mean, like, re-adding to the--
听众：您的意思是，例如，重新添加-
PROFESSOR: So an operation is a data structure operation,
教授：因此，操作是一种数据结构操作，
like a query or an update.
例如查询或更新。
This is my update and this is my query.
这是我的更新，这是我的查询。
AUDIENCE: Wait, but like, it's order n though, because--
听众：等等，但是，它的顺序是n，因为-
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: I know, it's order n.
听众：我知道，是n号命令。
But because we have like an array,
但是因为我们就像一个数组，
and then you have to make a new one,
然后必须重新制作一个
and you have to move all those old items over, right?
而且您必须将所有这些旧物品移走，对吗？
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
But, I mean, sometimes like, if your actual array,
但是，我的意思是，有时就像，如果您的实际阵列，
if you expand it before-- like, let's say you notice
如果您之前进行过扩展-例如，假设您注意到了
you're getting full and you decide to like make it bigger
你吃饱了，决定决定做大一点
at that point, is it still order n,
在那个时候，它仍然是n阶吗？
as in the number of elements that are--
如元素的数量-
PROFESSOR: It depends on how you decide.
教授：这取决于您的决定方式。
There's a problem on the PSET that asks you about that.
PSET上有一个问题询问您。
So, depends on when you make the decision
因此，取决于您何时做出决定
and how you make the decision, the answer is either yes,
以及如何做出决定，答案是肯定的，
you're still constant time, or no.
您仍然是固定时间，还是没有。
So if you understand the amortized analysis then
因此，如果您了解摊销分析，
you can argue of whether it still holds or not.
您可以争论它是否仍然成立。
If this breaks down at any point,
如果在任何时候出现故障，
not going to be constant time.
不会是固定的时间。
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: So the only cost is really copying everything
听众：所以唯一的代价就是复制所有内容
from the old array to the new array?
从旧阵列到新阵列？
PROFESSOR: Yes.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: Actually allocating that space is--
听众：实际上分配空间是-
PROFESSOR: We assume that allocating the space
教授：我们假设分配空间
is constant time.
是恒定的时间。
Good question, because you can't take that for granted, right?
好问题，因为您不能认为这是理所当然的，对吧？
So we assume that this is order 1, copying is order n.
因此，我们假设这是订单1，复制是订单n。
And then the insertion is order 1, just like before.
然后插入是顺序1，就像以前一样。
So allocating may not be constant.
因此分配可能不是恒定的。
In real life, allocating is actually
在现实生活中，分配实际上是
logarithmic either of the size that you're asking for
您所要求的大小的对数
or logarithmic of how many buffers you've allocated.
或分配了多少个缓冲区的对数。
And you can make a constant time allocator.
您可以创建一个恒定的时间分配器。
But that's lower than a logarithmic allocator,
但这比对数分配器低，
because the constant factor behind it is so big.
因为它背后的恒定因素是如此之大。
But even if this allocation would
但是即使这种分配会
be order n, which would be terrible,
是n阶，那将是可怕的，
it would still get absorbed here.
它仍然会在这里被吸收。
So the overall model works no matter what the allocation is.
因此，无论分配是什么，整体模型都可以工作。
It's reasonable, from a theoretical standpoint,
从理论上讲，这是合理的，
to say that allocation is order 1,
说分配是订单1，
from a theoretical standpoint.
从理论上讲。
So this is the real cost copying the elements.
这就是复制元素的实际成本。
And this makes an append order n worst case.
这会使追加命令成为最坏的情况。
So if you look at this data structure then
因此，如果您查看此数据结构，则
suppose we want to compute the cost of an append.
假设我们要计算附加成本。
So say we have code like this, 4, 1, 2, n.
可以这么说，我们有这样的代码4，1，2，n。
First we have L be an empty list.
首先，我们让L为空列表。
Then we want to compute the cost of this.
然后我们要计算成本。
So if we do it without amortized analysis,
因此，如果我们不进行摊销分析，
line by line analysis, just like we
逐行分析，就像我们
learned in the first lecture, what's the cost of this,
在第一堂课中学到的，这要花多少钱，
making a new list constant?
使新列表不变？
What's the cost of one append?
一个追加的费用是多少？
AUDIENCE: Constant.
听众：不变。
PROFESSOR: One append.
教授：一个附录。
So an append can either branch here or branch here.
因此，追加可以在此处分支或在此处分支。
So what's the cost of one append?
那么一个追加的费用是多少？
AUDIENCE: It would be showing with an empty list?
听众：会显示一个空列表吗？
AUDIENCE: Depends.
听众：取决于。
PROFESSOR: It depends.
教授：这取决于。
So worst case.
所以最坏的情况。
We have to look at a worst case.
我们必须考虑最坏的情况。
So this is line by line analysis.
因此，这是逐行分析。
We're going to get one number for this.
我们将为此获得一个号码。
AUDIENCE: N.
听众：N.
AUDIENCE: An n.
听众：
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
So in the worst case, the list will be full.
因此，在最坏的情况下，列表将是完整的。
And you'll have to make a new one.
而且您必须重新制作一个。
And then you're going on this branch of the if,
然后您进入if的这一分支，
so the cost is order n.
因此成本为订单n。
So order n, worst case.
因此，最糟糕的情况是命令n。
So the cost of one call is order n, worst case.
因此，一次通话的费用为n级（最坏的情况）。
How many calls do we make?
我们打多少个电话？
So what is the total cost of this thing?
那么这东西的总成本是多少？
AUDIENCE: It's not actually n squared.
听众：实际上不是n平方。
PROFESSOR: Yes, it's not actually n squared.
教授：是的，实际上不是n平方。
But if we do line by line analysis,
但是如果我们逐行进行分析，
before we learn amortized analysis,
在我们学习摊销分析之前，
all we can say it's order of n squared.
我们所能说的是n阶的平方。
And this is correct, it's not bigger than n squared, right?
这是正确的，它不大于n平方，对吗？
So O is correct.
所以O是正确的。
But it's not the tight bound.
但这不是界限。
So if we had a multiple choice, and you selected this,
因此，如果我们有多个选择，而您选择了这个，
you wouldn't get the score because we usually ask you
您不会得到分数，因为我们通常会问您
what the tightest bound that you can get.
您可以获得的最严格的限制。
OK, so line by line analysis.
好的，所以逐行分析。
We worked through that a lot in doc dist.
我们在doc dist中做了很多工作。
Doesn't work all the time.
并不是一直都在工作。
When it doesn't work, we tell you
当它不起作用时，我们告诉您
to use amortized analysis instead.
而是使用摊销分析。
So what's the goal of amortized analysis?
那么，摊销分析的目的是什么？
What do we want?
我们想要什么？
You guys are yelling at me that this is not n squared, why?
你们在对我大喊，这不是n平方，为什么？
I mean not why, what?
我的意思不是为什么，什么？
What is it instead?
那是什么呢？
What do we want from amortized analysis?
我们希望从摊销分析中得到什么？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
AUDIENCE: It's a [INAUDIBLE] that's an n.
听众：这是[听不清]，是n。
PROFESSOR: So we want amortized analysis
教授：所以我们要摊销分析
to say that this is order 1 amortized, and this is--
说这是订单1的摊销额，这是-
[ALARM SOUNDING]
[警报声音]
PROFESSOR: Am I out of time?
教授：我没时间吗？
Yeah.
是的
OK, so there's a difference between the worst
好，所以最差的
case and amortized, right?
案并摊销吧？
We can argue that this is order 1 amortized.
我们可以说这是订单1的摊销额。
And if this is order 1 amortized,
如果这是订单1的摊销额，
then this is order n amortized.
那么这是订单n摊销。
So does the difference between worst case and amortized
最坏情况与摊销之间的差异也是如此
make sense now?
现在有意义吗？
So this is what I want, the rest is fancy math.
这就是我想要的，剩下的就是花哨的数学。
If you forget the fancy math after you're
如果您忘记了花哨的数学
done with this class, that's OK.
完成本课后，就可以了。
If you remember that this is order 1 amortized,
如果您还记得这是订单1的摊销额，
and that's order n amortized, that's good.
那是分期付款的顺序，那很好。
That's all you need to know to write code
这就是编写代码所需的全部知识
if you don't design algorithms.
如果您不设计算法。
So this is an important piece of knowledge on its own.
因此，这本身就是重要的知识。
OK, so questions about the difference between worst case
好的，所以有关最坏情况之间的区别的问题
and amortized?
摊销？
OK, what does amortized mean?
好，摊销意味着什么？
AUDIENCE: Average.
听众：一般。
PROFESSOR: Yep, averaged out over multiple operations.
教授：是的，对多个操作取平均值。
So instead of doing line by line analysis,
因此，与其进行逐行分析，
we have to look at what happens over multiple operations,
我们必须看看多个操作会发生什么，
right?
对？
So there are two methods that I think are useful in CLRS.
因此，我认为有两种方法在CLRS中很有用。
There are three in total, but the last one
一共有三个，但最后一个
is horribly complicated.
非常复杂。
So there's something called aggregate analysis.
因此，有一种叫做汇总分析的东西。
And there's something called the cost based accounting.
还有一种叫做基于成本的会计。
So last time when we looked at the costs for append,
因此，上次查看附加费用时，
we argued that, hey, it's order 1 for a lot of times.
我们争辩说，嘿，很多次都是1。
And then it's only order n for an operation
然后只有一个操作的n
that's a power of 2.
那是2的幂。
So if we're looking at the K-ith append,
因此，如果我们查看第K个附加项，
then this is order K for K equals 2 to the i.
那么这就是K的阶数K等于i。
And it's order 1 otherwise.
否则为1。
Right?
对？
So if we sum up all these costs, we
因此，如果我们汇总所有这些费用，
get-- plus sum over log n of O of 2 to the i.
得到-加2的O的对数n到i的总和。
And this is clearly order n.
这显然是命令n。
And if you do the math here, this is also order n.
如果您在此处进行数学运算，则该阶也为n。
So this is aggregate analysis.
这就是聚合分析。
This is what we taught you in lecture.
这就是我们在讲座中教给您的。
Does this make sense?
这有意义吗？
So the key here is that whenever we are increasing the array,
所以这里的关键是，每当我们增加数组时，
we're increasing it to 2 times.
我们将其增加到2倍。
And we start with a size of 1, count is 1.
我们从1开始，计数为1。
We start with an array with 1 element.
我们从一个包含1个元素的数组开始。
So the size of the array will first
因此，数组的大小将首先
be 1, then 2, then 4, then 8, then 16, 32, 64, 128,
依次为1、2、4、8、16、32、64、128，
so on so forth.
依此类推。
It increases exponentially.
它成倍增加。
So on the first append I'll have to do a resize.
因此，在第一个附录中，我将需要调整大小。
On the second one, resize.
在第二个上，调整大小。
Fourth one, resize.
第四，调整大小。
Eighth, resize, so on and so forth.
第八，调整大小，依此类推。
So if I'm adding up the cost for n operations,
因此，如果我将n次操作的费用加起来，
each operation is order 1 because I'm
每个操作都是订单1，因为我
inserting everywhere.
随处插入。
And then all these operations are all order n.
然后所有这些操作都为n阶。
But there's few of them.
但是很少。
They're few and far out.
他们很少而且很遥远。
So if you write the sum this way, and you do the math,
因此，如果您以这种方式写总和，然后进行数学计算，
you get that it's order n.
您得到的是订单n。
So aggregate analysis says, look at n operations
所以汇总分析说，看一下n个运算
and add the costs up together.
并把成本加起来
And last time we had that good example of walking over a tree,
上次我们有一个很好的例子，那就是走在树上
and in order traversal where we drew arrows across edges.
为了遍历，我们在边缘画了箭头。
So that's aggregate analysis.
这就是汇总分析。
And then you should look at the cost method in CLRS
然后，您应该查看CLRS中的费用方法
because that's also useful sometimes.
因为有时候这也很有用。
Does this help?
这有帮助吗？
Any questions?
任何问题？
No, everyone wants to go home.
不，每个人都想回家。
AUDIENCE: Wait--
听众：等等-
PROFESSOR: Almost.
教授：差不多了。
AUDIENCE: For log n, so you're starting from log n going to--
听众：对于日志n，所以您从日志n开始-
PROFESSOR: So I'm starting from 1 going to log n.
教授：所以我从1开始要登录n。
AUDIENCE: Oh, oh, so [INAUDIBLE] after you're buffering.
听众：哦，哦，所以缓冲后[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: So this is fancy math for saying only
教授：所以这只是说说而已
add up powers of two.
将两个的幂加起来。
So that's what I'm trying to say, add these guys up.
这就是我要说的，把这些家伙加起来。
AUDIENCE: Well that's your step [INAUDIBLE].
听众：这就是您的步骤[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
AUDIENCE: Oh, OK.
听众：哦，好。
Oh, I like that.
哦，我喜欢。
OK.
好。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。